From House Arrest to Parliament
The Lady is a drama, romance film directed by Luc Besson.
The story of Aung San Suu Kyi as she becomes the core of Burma's democracy
movement, and her relationship with her husband, writer Michael Aris.
Lucinda Philips, played by Susan Wooldridge.
Aung San Suu Kyi, played by Michelle Yeoh.
Michael Aris, played by David Thewlis.
Kim Aris, played by Jonathan Raggett.
Alexander Aris, played by Jonathan Woodhouse.
Karma Phuntsho, played by Benedict Wong.
The Lady is a 2011 British biographical film directed by Luc Besson, starring Michelle
Yeoh as Aung San Suu Kyi and David Thewlis as her late husband Michael Aris.
Yeoh called the film "a labour of love" but also confessed it had
felt intimidating for her to play the Nobel laureate.
The film explores themes of police brutality, seer,
massacre, political assassination, human rights.
The tone is dark and emotional.